Guide to the Tom Rankin photographs and papers, 1977-2016 RL.10043
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Tom Rankin photographs and papers
1977-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rankin, Tom
RL.10043
33.5 Linear Feet 28 boxes; 2 film reels Approximately 13,650 items
Tom Rankin is a documentary photographer, filmmaker, folklorist, professor of art and documentary studies, and former director of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University. Collection consists of 147 black-and-white and color photographs documenting the American South and China. Photographs from the South focus on religious sites, rituals, and communities in the Mississippi Delta region, as well as portraits of individuals, including portraits of Mississippi writer Larry Brown, and Southern landscapes. An additional documentary project from 2016 took Rankin to China, where he photographed semi-rural landscapes, often taken with high-rise buildings in the far distance or adjacent to industrial structures, as well as bridges and rivers, markets and live fish vendors, and a few street scenes. Finished prints range from 8x11 inch contact prints to 11x14, 16x20, and 20x24 large-format prints. Supporting materials include manuscripts, publications files, and two films, all deriving from Rankin's career and art practice. Includes a digital audio recording of a talk by Rankin at the exhibit opening of his work, "Near the Cross: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta." Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
33.5 linear feet; approximately 13,640 items
Biographical Note
Tom Rankin served as the Director of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University for three consecutive five-year terms until 2013, and is a Professor of the Practice in the Arts and Director of the Master of Fine Arts program at Duke University. A documentary photographer, filmmaker, writer, editor, and folklorist, he has been documenting and interpreting American culture, particularly in the South, for nearly twenty years. His photographic work has been published and widely exhibited. His most long-standing work has been to reveal through the documentary arts the culture and society of the Mississippi Delta region, where he also served as a faculty member of Delta State University and the University of Mississippi. He has returned many times since the 1980s to photograph the landscapes and people of the Mississippi Delta, most recently in 2011 after the great floods of that year.
His books include Sacred Space: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta (1993), which received the Mississippi Institute of Arts and Letters Award for Photography, 'Deaf Maggie Lee Sayre': Photographs of a River Life(1995), Faulkner's World: The Photographs of Martin J. Dain (1997), and Local Heroes Changing America: Indivisible (2000).
He received an MFA from Georgia State University and an MA from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. American Photo Magazine named Tom Rankin as one of the 100 Most Important People in Photography, May, 2005.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, original recordings and films are closed to use. Viewing or listening copies may need to be made for access.
Also, publication and commercial use of any kind requires the permission of the photographer.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Tom Rankin photographs and papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts and purchases from 2007 to 2018.
Collection Overview
The photographic work of Tom Rankin in this collection consists of 147 black-and-white and color photographs documenting the American South and China. Southern photographs were taken from 1980 to 2007, and focus on religious sites, rituals, and communities in the Mississippi Delta region; these prints form the largest series, "Sacred Space." Another body of work features portraits of Mississippi writer Larry Brown. A third body of work, "Portraits from the American South," offers views of Southern people, cultures, and landscapes in both color and black-and-white.
An additional documentary project from 2016 took Rankin to China, where he photographed semi-rural landscapes, often taken with high-rise buildings in the far distance or adjacent to industrial structures, as well as bridges and rivers, markets and live fish vendors, and a few street scenes.
Print sizes range from 11x14, 13x19, 16x20, and 20x24 inches, with many housed in window mats. Along with these prints, there are also 8x11 inch black-and-white matted contact prints. All titles were created by the photographer.
Selected photographs from this collection have been exhibited at the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke and other locations. A selection of Rankin's photographs was published in a book, Sacred Space: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta (1993).
Supporting materials in this collection include a digital audio recording of a talk by Rankin at the exhibit opening of work from the Sacred Space series, "Near the Cross: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta," as well as paper records related to his career and art practice, including book publications and book layouts. Also in the collection are two motion films, Dance Like a River (1985), directed by Barry Dorfeld and Tom Rankin, and Four Women Artists (1977), directed by Bill Ferris.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Conditions Governing Access note
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
Collection Arrangement
The photographic materials are arranged in four main series by bodies of work: Larry Brown; Sacred Space: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta; Portraits From the American South; and Photographs from China. These series are followed by Other Photographic Work, Manuscripts and Recordings, and Other Audiovisual Materials.
African Americans -- Mississippi; Church buildings -- Southern States -- Pictorial works; Documentary Photography -- China; Documentary photographers -- North Carolina; Documentary Photography -- United States; Religion -- Pictorial works; Religious communities -- Mississippi; China -- Photographs; Kunshan Shi (China) -- Photographs; Mississippi -- Pictorial works; Mississippi -- Religious life; Mississippi -- Social life and customs; Southern States -- Photographs; Audiovisual materials; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Contact prints; Documentaries (motion picture genre); Gelatin silver prints; Inkjet prints; mp3 files; Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Rankin, Tom; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Brown, Larry, 1951-2004
- Larry Brown, 1993-1997, 2004; 1; 20 prints
  Scope and Contents
  Series consists of portraits of Mississippi writer Larry Brown with his family and friends in Mississippi. Arranged in original order as received; all titles were created by the photographer. Unless otherwise noted, all prints are 11x14 inch unmatted gelatin silver prints; three color pigment inkjet prints are also present.
  - Larry Brown in his garden, Yocona, Mississippi, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0001)
  - Charlie Jacobs funeral, Bolivar County, Mississippi, 1997 (Larry Brown far left) (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0002)
  - Larry Brown and Charlie Jacobs, Larry's pond, Tula, Mississippi, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0003)
  - Larry Brown, Oxford, Mississippi, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0004)
  - Larry Brown riding in my truck, Yocona to Tula, Mississippi 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0005)
  - Larry Brown, Tula, Mississippi, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0006)
  - Larry Brown at home, Yocona, Mississippi, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0007)
  - Mary Annie Brown and Larry Brown, Tula, Mississippi, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0008)
  - Larry Brown, on my porch, Jefferson Avenue, Oxford, Mississippi, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0009)
  - Larry Brown cleaning deer, Yocona, Mississippi, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0010)
  - Larry Brown at my house, Oxford, Mississippi, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0011)
  - Larry Brown, Tula, Mississippi, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0012)
  - Larry Brown, Tula, Mississippi, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0013)
  - Mary Annie and Larry Brown, Yocona, Mississippi, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0014)
  - Jonny Miles and Larry Brown, Bear Creek, Mississippi, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0015)
  - Larry Brown, Bear Creek, Mississippi, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0016)
  - Larry Brown, Oxford, Mississippi, circa 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0017)
    Inkjet color print, 16x20 inches
  - Larry Brown and Richard Howorth, Larry's pond, Tula, Mississippi, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0018)
    Inkjet color print, 13x16 inches
  - Larry Brown and Richard Howorth on dock at Larry's pond, Tula, Mississippi, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0019)
  - Larry Brown, Tula, Mississippi, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0020)
- Sacred Space: Photographs From the Mississippi Delta, 1989-1992, 2006-2007; 2; 62 prints
  This body of work comprises 62 black-and-white prints that document and reflect on spiritual and religious practices in the rural Mississippi Delta region of the Southern United States, with a focus on churches, pastors and congregations, cemetery sites, and baptisms. Selected images were published in "Sacred Space: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta," and exhibited in 2008 at Duke University as "Near the Cross: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta."
  The artist offers his reflection on the project: "No single institution in the Delta region has had a more profound impact on the entire culture of the Mississippi Delta than the countless African-American churches that accent the landscape. The ubiquitous presence of these churches and their adjoining cemeteries and churchyards - these sacred spaces - constitutes a kind of three-dimensional iconography in an otherwise profane agricultural landscape. Landmarks to some, places of spiritual refuge to others, 'home church' to their devoted members, these centers of religious and social life have been planned, built, decorated, and maintained by local communities for heartfelt reasons...Thus the look and life of the church, inside and out, reflect the attitudes, beliefs, aspirations, and realities of the community...The church survives not only as a place of worship, but also as a symbol to the membership of a sacred home where a formal commitment to religion began, where family meets, and where forebears once gathered."
  The prints in this series come in many sizes and processes: 11x14 inch unmatted black-and-white gelatin silver prints (box 2); 11x14 gelatin silver prints in 16x20 inch mats (box 7); 16x20 inch unmatted prints (boxes 4-5); and 16x20 inch gelatin silver prints in 20x24 inch mats (box 6). Prints in Box 3 are 8 1/2 x 11 contact prints, with slight variations, in 11x14 inch window mats; there are a few prints in this group that have larger finished print versions in the collection. Within size categories, prints are arranged in order as assigned by the photographer. All titles are original.
  - Reverend Brooks Tobe, at his home in Rosedale, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0021)
  - Reverend Tom Bronner and his niece, New Bethel M.B. Church, Perthshire, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0022)
  - Baptism, Moon Lake, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0023)
  - Baptism, Jerusalem M.B. Church, Mound Bayou, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0024)
  - Deacon Fred Davis, Moon Lake, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0025)
  - Baptism, three at time, Moon Lake, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0026)
  - Mt Pleasant M.B. Church, Beulah, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0027)
  - Grave of Matilda Wray, Sunflower County, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0028)
    A large-format print version is also in collection.
  - Mt. Olive Church, near Beulah, Mississippi, 1992 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0029)
  - Reverend Tom Bronner with neighborhood children, Gunnison, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0030)
  - New Hope M.B. Church, Shelby, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0031)
  - Hand-painted window, A.M.E. Church, Indianola, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0032)
  - Interior of Bethlehem M.B. Church No. 2, Shaw, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0033)
  - Reverend E.B. Brown at pulpit, Mt. Pleasant M.B. Church, Beulah, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0034)
  - Handmade gravestones, Mound Bayou, 1989 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0035)
  - Paper Easter flowers, near Tchula, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 3, Image RL-10043-P-0036)
  - Evening Star Baptist Church, undated (Box 4, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0037)
  - Mt. Olive Church, near Beulah, Mississippi, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0038)
    A smaller contact print version is also in collection.
  - Grave of Matilda Wray, Sunflower County, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0039)
  - Chester Arthur Burke, Rosedale, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0040)
  - Steeple on Margaret's Market, Vicksburg, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0041)
  - Interior of Chester Arthur Burke M.B. Church, Rosedale, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0042)
  - Percy, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0043)
  - Pleasant Green M.B. Church, Rolling Fork, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0044)
  - Reverend Tom Bronner at home, Gunnison, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0045)
  - Mt. Tinnia M.B. Church, Scott, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0046)
  - New Hope M.B. Church, Shelby, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0047)
  - St. James M.B. Church, Jonestown, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0048)
  - Pleasant Green M.B. Church, Rolling Fork, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0049)
  - Church on the Shaw-Litton Road at Sunset, Bolivar County, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0050)
  - Shellmound, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0051)
  - Holly Bluff, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0052)
  - Chester Arthur Burke M.B. Church, Rosedale, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0053)
  - Mt. Tinnia M.B. Church, near Scott, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0054)
  - Mt. Tinnia M.B. Church, near Scott, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0055)
    Same church as in print -0054, seen at more of a distance.
  - Little Ebenezer Baptist Church, Rosedale, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1, Image RL-10043-P-0056)
  - Near Shelby, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0057)
  - Paper Easter flowers, near Tchula, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0058)
  - Reverend Tom Bronner with neighborhood children, Gunnison, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0059)
  - Reverend E.B. Brown, Mt. Pleasant M.B. Church, Beulah, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0060)
  - Morning Star M.B. Church, Beulah, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0061)
  - Reverend Herman Dennis, Margaret's Grocery, Vicksburg, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0062)
  - Alfred Green Grave, Beulah, Mississippi, 2007 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0063)
  - St. James M.B. Church, Jonestown, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0064)
  - Bethlehem M.B. Church No. 2, Shaw, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0065)
  - Reverend Brooks Tobe, Little Ebenezer Baptist Church, Rosedale, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0066)
  - Brooks Chapel M.B. Church, Greenwood, Mississippi, 2006 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0067)
  - Abundant Life, Highway 1, Washington County, Mississippi, 2007 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0068)
  - Holly Bluff, Mississippi, 2007 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0069)
  - Near Litton, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0070)
  - Mt. Tinnia M.B. Church, Scott, Mississippi, 2007 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0071)
  - New Hope Church, Estill, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 6, Image RL-10043-P-0072)
  - Deacon Fred Davis, Moon Lake, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0073)
  - Baptism, Jerusalem M.B. Church, Mound Bayou, 1989 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0074)
  - Moon Lake, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0075)
  - Candidate for baptism, Perthshire, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0076)
  - Juandra Griffin and Venita Murray, Moon Lake, 1990 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0077)
  - Prayer after baptism, 1990 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0078)
  - Congregation, Bethlehem No. 2, Shaw, Mississippi, circa 1991 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0079)
  - Baptism of Cheronda Brown by Reverend Crabtree, Stamps Lake, 1990 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0080)
  - Baptism, Moon Lake, 1990 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0081)
  - Candidate for Baptism, 1990 (Box 7, Image RL-10043-P-0082)
- Portraits from the American South, 1980-1993; 3; 30 prints
  Images of individuals, cemeteries, businesses, and landscapes taken by Rankin in various Southern states, including Alabama, Georgia, Mississippi, and Virginia. Includes 16x20 inch unmatted vintage chromogenic prints (box 8) and 11x14 inch black-and-white gelatin silver prints in 16x20 inch mats (box 9). Arranged in original order as received. All titles were created by the photographer.
  - Sonny Boy Williams grave, Tutwiler, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0083)
  - Columbus, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0084)
  - Crystal Springs, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0085)
  - Oakley and Manuel, Sunflower County, Mississippi, circa 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0086)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0087)
  - W.C. Rice Cross Garden, Prattville, Alabama, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0088)
  - Sunflower County, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0089)
  - Near Litton, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0090)
  - Meridian, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 3, Image RL-10043-P-0091)
  - E.T. Wickham statue, Palmyra, Tennessee, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4, Image RL-10043-P-0092)
  - Hand-painted window, Indianola, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4, Image RL-10043-P-0093)
  - New Hope Church, Shelby, Mississippi, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 4, Image RL-10043-P-0094)
  - Ichauway Plantation, Baker County, Georgia, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4, Image RL-10043-P-0095)
  - Mary T. Smith's house, Hazelhurst, Mississippi, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 4, Image RL-10043-P-0096)
  - Mary T. Smith scarecrow, Hazelhurst, Mississippi, circa 1986 (Box 8, Folder 5, Image RL-10043-P-0097)
  - W.C. Rice's Chapel, Prattville, Alabama, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 5, Image RL-10043-P-0098)
  - Hand-painted windows, Indianola, Mississippi, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5, Image RL-10043-P-0099)
  - Jewell Thomas, Carrollton, Mississippi, undated (Box 8, Folder 5, Image RL-10043-P-0100)
  - Manuel, Sunflower County, Mississippi, circa 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5, Image RL-10043-P-0101)
  - A.M.E. Church, Indianola, Mississippi, undated (Box 8, Folder 5, Image RL-10043-P-0102)
  - Stanford Boyd at home, Louisville, Kentucky, 1980 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0103)
  - Andrew Jones, Ripley, Tennessee, 1981 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0104)
  - Portrait outside Geronimo's Bar, Texas, 1980 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0105)
  - Marlow at home, Linden, Tennessee, 1982 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0106)
  - Roanoke, Virginia, 1980 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0107)
  - Man with Chevelle, Highway 86, Orange County, North Carolina, 1980 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0108)
  - Fred Rushing, Benton County, Tennessee, 1981 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0109)
  - Ed Hunt, Tennessee River, near Savannah, Tennessee, 1982 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0110)
  - Garvin Tuberville, at home with mussel boat, 1982 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0111)
  - Near Linden, Tennessee, 1982 (Box 9, Image RL-10043-P-0112)
- Photographs from China, 2016; 34 prints 3 boxes
  These black-and-white gelatin silver photographs were taken by Tom Rankin while in Kunshan, China in 2016 and printed by Rankin in 2018. Sizes of prints range from 11x14 (9), 16x20 (18), and 20x24 inches (3). Scenes include rural landscapes surrounding the Duke University Kunshan campus; canals and barges; a fish market; vegetable gardens tended by lone figures, often in the shadow of industrial structures; an abandoned theme park; and religious shrines.
  - Farmer's shelter in field adjacent to DKU, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0114)
    Selenium toned contact print, 11x14 inches
    Title (Chinese)
    杜克昆山大学校园旁农田里的小棚子
  - Shutougang Bridge, with legumes drying and Peking Resource Center in background, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0115)
    竖头港桥, 田里干枯的豆荚，后面是北京信息中心
  - Shutougang Bridge and Peking Resource Center, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0116)
    竖头港桥，北京信息中心，2016
  - Detail of Shutougang Bridge in front of DKU, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0117)
    昆山杜克大学前的竖头港桥细节，2016
  - Fish market by the river in Bacheng, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0118)
    Selenium toned print, 14x11 inches
    巴城镇河边的鱼市，2016
  - Bicycles and map, Kunshan, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0119)
    14x11 inch print
    自行车和地图，昆山，2016
  - Fish market, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0120)
    鱼市，巴城镇，2016
  - Fresh fish hanging by Zhang Xin Dyke, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0121)
    张新塘堤岸上挂着的鲜鱼，巴城镇，2016
  - Wu Wenguang in front of noodle restaurant, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0122)
    吴文光站在一家面馆前，巴城镇，2016
  - Barge gathering trash from the river, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0123)
    河中打捞垃圾的驳船，巴城镇，2016
  - Fish market, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0124)
  - Field workers in front of DKU campus, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0125)
    杜克昆山大学校园前田里劳作的人们，2016
  - Family dog in market, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 26, Image RL.10043-P-0126)
    市场里摊主的一只狗，巴城镇，2016
  - Tree across Zhang Xin Dyke, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0127)
    Selenium toned print, 16x20 inches
    张新塘堤岸上的树木，巴城镇
  - Bridge across Zhang Xin Dyke, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0128)
    张新塘上的桥，巴城镇
  - Vegetable fields by canal, near DKU, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0129)
    运河旁的蔬菜地，杜克昆山大学校园附近
  - Lotus candles at shrine by Zhang Xin Dyke, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0130)
    16x20 inch print
    张新塘附近庙里的莲花灯
  - Agricultural field with bicycle, near DKU, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0131)
    农田里的自行车，杜克昆山大学附近
  - Tree, bridge, and man by Zhang Xin Dyke, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0132)
    张新塘周围的树木，桥和人们
  - Altar inside shrine, Zhang Xin Dyke, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0133)
    庙里的供桌，张新塘，巴城镇
  - Canal and pipe, Kunshan, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0134)
    运河和管道，昆山市
  - Barge on Zhang Xin Dyke, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0135)
    张新塘上的驳船
  - Abandoned theme park with legumes drying, Kunshan, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0136)
    废弃的主题公园，枯萎的豆荚，昆山市
  - Grove of painted trees, Kunshan, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0137)
    一片树林里树干都涂了白色，昆山市
  - Agricultural field in front of DKU, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0138)
    杜克昆山大学前的农田